Ken Blizzard-Caron

ken.blizzardcaron@gmail.com | 603.801.8236 | Austin, TX | kenblizzardcaron.com

INTRODUCTION

I'm a dedicated Austin-based developer. I have ten years of professional programming experience designing and engineering web apps, video games, and wearable apps. I love to code. When I'm not learning a new framework you can often find me camping with my wife and dog, discovering new vegan restaurants, roasting coffee, or training for a race.

EXPERIENCE

INDEED | UX DEVELOPER

Austin, TX | 2019 - Present

• I develop mobile and desktop experiences in React for employers of small & midsize businesses that are hiring job seekers. I collaborate with designers, software engineers, researchers and mangers daily. I employ use of our design system and use best practices to make scalable, accessible, performant, and themeable web experiences for our customers. Our application is served worldwide, employs data-driven experimentation, and effective unit and integration testing.

PLUMRIVER LLC / CENTERSTONE TECHNOLOGIES | Software Engineer Denver, CO | 2014 - 2019

• At CST I Introduced AngularJS to the ColdFusion stack of their flagship iVendix product: a highly customizable eCommerce B2B application. I led frontend development on the next generation of iVendix which employs Angular 5 and a RESTful Node, is API. I also developed various client-specific applications and features, with the most sizable ones being for New Balance, Ariat, and Patagonia. CST was acquired by this ambitious startup and I started working on their flagship Elastic Suite product which is used by many high profile clients such as The North Face, QuikSilver, and Puma. Here I employed React, Rails, and MongoDB to deliver several new features, components, and tests. I had significant contributions to their UI Refresh initiative in the spring, and also focused on custom payment processing.

MOCAVO Boulder, CO | 2011 - 2013

• I was an early hire at this Techstars backed genealogy startup that was acquired by Findmypast in 2014. I took lead roles in many crucial features of the site including advanced search, the family-tree creator, document viewer, and the contributions stream. I also supported search-engine crawling, scraping, and indexing.

NOTE

 More complete work history dating back to 2009 available upon request. Companies include Vote Foundation, Torch LLC, MetricFeat LLC, Rabble+Rouser, Giveo, Hoozinga, and Mt. Mansfield Media.

PROFICIENCIES

AGILE & WATERFALL METHODOLOGIES, ANGULAR, ANGULARJS, BACKBONE.JS, C++, CSS, CODEIGNITER, COLDFUSION, CROSS-BROWSER COMPATIBILITY, DOCKER, DOJO, EXPRESS, FITBIT OS SDK, FLOW, GATSBYJS, GIT, GULP, HTML EMAIL TEMPLATING, HTML5, 118N, JASMINE, JAVASCRIPT, JERRYSCRIPT, JQUERY, JSX, LARAVEL, LODASH, MOCHA, MONGODB, MYSQL, NGINX, NGRX, NODE.JS, NPM, PEBBLE SDK, PHOTOSHOP, PHP, PUG, REACT, REDUX, RUBY ON RAILS, SASS, SKETCH, STYLED COMPONENTS, TACHYONS, TAPE, THREE.JS, TWITTER BOOTSTRAP, TYPESCRIPT, WEBPACK, WORDPRESS, YARN

EDUCATION

CHAMPLAIN COLLEGE | BS ELECTRONIC GAME & INTERACTIVE DEVELOPMENT Burlington, VT | 2005 - 2009

CHAMPLAIN COLLEGE | Professional Certificate C++ Burlington, VT | 2008 - 2009